Peter Talavera

Location: Gilbert, Arizona 85296 Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-talavera-97940aa1 Phone Number: (480) 299-5151

Email: petertfreelance@gmail.com

My name is Peter Talavera, I am a web developer with over 9 years of website development on e-commerce and blog websites. I have learned multiple programming languages including recent programming languages versions such as php8.1, html5, and CSS preprocessors, while also being a fast learner on other programming languages. I specialize in front end development however I have experience troubleshooting backend issues and developing backend functionality. I will help clients by identifying issues where their website can improve such as on SEO, performance or ADA compliance, as well as make suggestions for functionality or design aspects on their websites to help improve User Experience for both customer and client. Finally I always keep a professional attitude and am great at working with others. I make a great effort to always be on time and always make an effort to learn new things or improve on areas outside my comfort zone to broaden my skill set.

Skills:

I have great understanding in using both Wordpress and Magento platforms, as well as various themes for both platforms.

- 1. About 9 years of e-commerce experience
- 2. Proficient in Php 8.1, Mysql, Css, Less, Scss, Javascript, KO Javascript, ¡Query, ReactJs, Ajax, Xml, HTML5, Linux, GUI, PERL
- 3. Developed on Magento platforms for 8 years
- 4. 2 years of wordpress and woocommerce Developing and updating content and theme
- 5. Edited and implemented Wordpress plugins and magento extensions
- 6. Created New themes for websites and built to match mockups.
- 7. Style and layout for web pages (Including Responsive capabilities)
- 8. Improved websites for SEO, performance, and ADA compliance
- 9. Experience with presenting and organizing.
- 10. Experience in working with teams.

Programs I have used involve PhpStorm, Windows Powershell, Debian, Docker-sync, Docker Desktop, Win scp, Powershell, Putty, Magento 1 - Magento 2.4.5, Wordpress, Figma, Adobe PhotoShop, Illustrator, Excel, Word, Powerpoint, Git, Sourcetree, Bitbucket, and Putty.

Education:

Bachelors of Science – Computer Informatics Graduated in December 2015 Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

Relevant courses:

- **Decision Making and Problem Solving**
- Information Systems Engineering
- Web Design and Development
- Programing for the Web
- Programing for Media Arts
- **Informatics Capstone**

Informatics Capstone Project ASU (2014 – 2015)

Was part of a capstone project within Arizona State University. We recreated two games from the Working Memory Capacity Battery and created a feature in them in which the game would adapt depending on your performance and emotions. I helped test the program, gather information from participants with it, and helped write several reports on the project.

Magento 2 certificates:

- Magento 1 Certified Developer Plus (M1CDP) *
- Adobe Certified Professional Adobe Commerce Developer (Adobe Commerce)
- Adobe Certified Professional Adobe Commerce Front-End Developer (Adobe Commerce)
- Adobe Certified Expert Adobe Commerce Front End Developer (Adobe Commerce)

Work Experience

E-commerce Engineer

Crimson Agility

February 2016 - July 2024

Responsible for frontend styling and layout on websites, creating modules and extensions for requested functionality, troubleshooting issues and managing product data.

Job involved Primarily developing the theme, creating modules, importing/exporting data, installing extensions, installing security patches, and updating or adding content of the site:

https://www.performancehealth.com/

https://www.gumballs.com/

http://www.cramersportsmed.com/

https://www.rdbatteries.com/

https://www.highspeedgear.com/

https://www.comp-tac.com/

https://novosurgical.com/

https://store.cumminsallison.com/

https://selectmedical.performancehealth.com/

https://shop.betaclub.org/

https://www.brookmays.com/

Web Designer/Developer

DKD Arts

May 2015 - February 2016

Responsible for creating and designing websites for various clients as well as communicated with them to meet their needs for project completion.

Websites helped built and developed for:

http://chillsairconditioning.com

http://executive-digital.com

http://migvapor.com

http://beachcats.org/

http://fengshuibyjen.com

http://citationpros.com

http://drsheryl.net (wooCommerce)

http://cre8able.com

http://dkdarts.com

References:

Patrick Traynor: 480-292-4691 Anais Almirall: 480-395-6640 Joshua Davis: 847-652-7822

Last Updated: September 7, 2024